# Benjamin T. Brier

Bala Cynwyd, Pennsylvania 19004 Phone: (484)844-4114 | Email: ben.brier14@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/BenjaminBrier | Github: https://github.com/BBrier14 |

Portfolio: https://bbrier14.github.io/MyPortfolio/

## **Summary**

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in the United States Army and a passion for creating unique and unparalleled technologies. Experienced in working with a team to develop innovative creations. Known for breaking down highly complex problems into manageable pieces in order to find efficient and effective solutions. Currently holding an active government Secret Security Clearance.

#### Technical Skills

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Java, and MYSQL.

**Applications:** Bootstrap, jQuery, Node.js, Command Line, Git, Github, Heroku, Express.js, React.js, MongoDB, AJAX, Firebase, Affinity Designer, and Affinity Photo.

#### **Projects**

**UFC Fight Club** | https://github.com/JackRyan1989/groupProject1 | https://jackryan1989.github.io/groupProject1/

- The UFC Fight Club App allows users to search for their favorite fighter, find an event, learn the history of the UFC, take a trivia quiz, or find the latest news.
- This application uses HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, and multiple API's.

Train Scheduler | https://github.com/BBrier14/Train-Activity | https://bbrier14.github.io/Train-Activity/

- This Train Scheduler application allows the user to input & check on imaginary train times.
- This application uses HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ¡Query, Firebase, and moment.js.

Dark Souls Game | https://github.com/BBrier14/Unit-4-Game | https://bbrier14.github.io/Unit-4-Game/

- The Dark Souls Game is a guessing game that includes some basic math to achieve a goal.
- This application uses HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, and iQuery.

#### **Work Experience**

## Pennsylvania National Guard | Corporal, 19D | August 2011 - Present

Currently Assigned to A-Troop, 1/104th CAV, a light reconnaissance unit, serving as a truck-commander in my platoon.

JDog Glenside/ JDog HQ | Marketing Manager - Operations Coordinator | December 2017- August 2019

Acted as the liaison between the franchisees and franchisor. Utilized standard and guerilla-marketing techniques to build brand loyalty and trust.

#### Triple Canopy | Force Protection Officer | November 2016 - November 2017

Performed defensive operations on a Special Operations, classified compound in Afghanistan.

# BKM Global Enterprises | Independent Contractor | May 2014 - October 2016

Acted as a surveillance role-player for the Joint Counter Intelligence Training Academy. Supported USASOC in training exercises.

# **Education & Organizations**

Penn LPS Coding Bootcamp Certificate: University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA

Bachelor's of Science, Criminal Justice: Rosemont College, Rosemont, PA

Corporal: First Troop Philadelphia City Cavalry, Philadelphia PA

Master Mason: St. Alban Lodge 529, Philadelphia, PA